All right, so in project three we're going to build our neural network.
好 在项目3中 我们将构建神经网络
That is going to predict whether or not a neural review has positive or
来预测一篇影评表达的是正面情感还是负面情感
negative sediment by using the counts of words that are inside of our review.
方法就是对影评中出现的单词进行计数
Now the changes I made first were, to create a pre process data function, that
我做的第一步 就是创建一个数据预处理函数
just brings in all the kind of little snippets that we built and tested above.
将我们之前构造并测试过的各个小块串在一起
So word to index, kind of the different vocabularies, and vocabulary sizes.
包括 word2index 不同的词汇 以及词汇表大小等
Just all of the variables that we used in our training dataset
那些我们在生成训练数据集逻辑中使用的变量
generation logic, I wanted to have it in a pre-processing data function,
我希望将它们都放在一个数据预处理函数中
so that it's all kind of self contained in the variables that are in this class.
这样 这些变量都存在于这个相对独立的类中
The next thing I did was, I split off the stuff that was in here into an init
接下来我做的 是将 int_network 函数拆分出来
network function, just to keep things clean, and
让这部分代码看起来更简洁明了
also this needs to know the number of input nodes, the number of output nodes.
而且 这个函数需要知道输入节点数 和输出节点数
Which is based on the number of reviews or unique vocabulary in our views, and
它们取决于共有多少条评论 或者有多少不重复词汇
the number of labels that we have.
以及我们一共有多少个标签
So it's nice to kind of have these in separate function,
所以 将函数分别独立出来挺好的
just so that you can kind of read the progress that's here, and
这样你通过查看函数名称就可以了解相关步骤
just clean it that way, I kind of like it.
清晰明了 我挺喜欢的
And the next thing it did was update input layer and set target for
接下来 我做的是 更新输入层 为标签设定目标值
label which are these functions that we played with before.
之前我们创建过它们的函数
I'm going to go ahead and move into the class just so
然后将它们移到类中
that it's all kind of self contained and together,
使这一类的功能齐全
and that makes this class portable, so I can use it somewhere else.
方便调用 我可以在其他地方使用它
All right, so
好
now on the training method, this is where most of the action is, right?
现在来看 train 函数 这就是步骤最多的地方
So the first thing I checked was that,
所以第一步 我要检查的是
the number of training reviews we have is the same as the number of labels.
待训练评论的数量与标签数量是否一致
So in the off chance someone input something that
以防人为输入了前后不一致的值
doesn't line up correctly, we kind of want to let people know,
这样可以提醒用户
so we see a kind of weird behavior in around that.
出现了异常输入
And the next thing we´re going to do is kind of intialize correct so far,
接下来 我们要做的就是 初始化一个 correct_so_far 值
we´re going keep track of how many predictions we get right and
用于统计到目前为止预测正确的数目
wrong while we´re training.
在训练过程中密切关注训练进展
This is a useful metric that I kind of like to watch to understand
这是一个很有用的指标 我喜欢用它来直观了解
how the neuromet is doing during the training process, right.
神经网络在训练过程中究竟表现如何
Is it getting better, is it not getting better at all, is it getting worse?
是越来越好 毫无进展 还是越来越糟？
These things are kind of the basics of understanding how you're doing and
这些都是最基本的帮你了解训练效果的方法
then being able to adjust for that.
让你可以据此优化网络
Now also we select review and
现在 我们从训练评论集中
a label out of our training reviews, we update the input layer.
选择一条评论和对应的标签 对输入层进行更新
This is the same as previously we were propagating from layer zero to layer
这类似于我们之前从第 0 层到第 1 层传播
one, or from your input layer to your hidden layer.
或者说 从输入层向隐藏层传播
However, in this case, we have to adjust and
但不同的是 这里 我们要先调整和生成输入数据集
generate our input data set first before we can do this propagation.
然后再进行传播运算
So now we generate hidden layer same way as before, except without nonlinearity,
所以现在 我们与之前一样生成隐藏层 只是它是线性的
and the last one will generate with nonlinearity.
最后一层 是非线性的
So that's our forward propagation step.
这些就是正向传播的步骤
Our back propagation step, the first thing we do.
接下来反向传播 第一步
How close did we, did we miss?
就是确定误差
This is where we put our function that we created.
在这里放入之前创建的函数
We say our prediction minus our function, and then because we
用预测值 减去函数所调用的实际标签值
have a nonlinearity on this layer our layer 2 delta has to multiply
由于该层具有非线性 所以要得到 layer_2_delta
by this function, which is sigmoid times 1 minus sigmoid.
乘数之一应为 sigmoid 的导数函数 即 sigmoid * (1 - sigmoid)
And then we continue to back propagate in this way.
然后 继续以这种方式做反向传播
Now a thing that you see we skip here is that because there's a nonlinearity on
你们可能注意到了 我未对第 1 层做反向传播
layer one, we don't do this multiplication step here, unlike before,
是因为第 1 层是线性的 我不用做类似的导数乘法
because this is a linear layer.
因为这是一个线性层
So we don't actually have to adjust for the not mislope of the non linearity.
我们不必像非线性一般调整斜率
Once we have our layer two and layer one deltas,
有了 layer_2_delta 和 layer_1_delta 后
we're ready to update our weights.
我们就可以更新权值了
Which you do here in the exact same way that we did in our previous
这和我们之前神经网络中的做法
neural network.
完全一样
And then add a little bit of logic just to kind of log our progress.
然后 稍微添加一些逻辑 来用日志记录训练过程
As well as see how fast we're training, and how many predictions we got correct.
看看训练速度多快 正确预测的数量有多少
Now how am I deciding whether we got something correct or not?
那么 我们如何判定是否预测对了呢？
What I'm looking at is the absolute value of our prediction, or,
我这里看到的 是预测值的绝对值
excuse me, the absolute value of the error of our prediction.
抱歉 是我们预测误差的绝对值
So up here we calculate the difference between what our prediction
所以在上面这里 我们计算两者差异 即预测结果
should be and what it was.
和实际值之间的差异
And so I said if it predicts exactly 0.5, well it didn't,
所以 我说 如果预测值正好是 0.5（虽然并没有）
it's totally ambiguous.
这就完全是模棱两可
It's kind of half way between positive and negative, it didn't pick either.
刚好处在正负的正中间 没有选择任何一项
But if it's closer to the right prediction,
但是 如果它更接近正确预测值
well then this error measure will be less than 0.5.
那么 这一误差测量值将小于 0.5
And so that's why I can kind of see how many classifications we got right,
所以我能看到 究竟预测正确了多少个
as opposed to just the loss by kind of just typing this on the fly, and
而不是只知道误差值是多少
then logging as we go.
因为电脑会一直记录日志
Now the other thing I want to be able to do here is test it.
这里 我想做的另一件事 就是测试它
Which is really just a matter of taking it for logic and
实际上就是 先对它做一个正向传播
in the evaluation logic, put that in a one function, which I did here.
再用一个评估逻辑 把它们作为一整个函数 就是我这里所做的
And then I add another one for running where we can put in a text review and
然后 我还定义了另一个运行函数：输入一段评论文本
it converts that text into an input data, and just forward pops and
它会将其转换成输入数据 经过正向传播
give POSITIVE, NEGATIVE labels.
得出 正标签 或 负标签
So we can test it on the whole data set or
所以 我们可以测试整个数据集
we can kind of throw in some examples and see whether we like it.
也可以对某些单独的样例进行测试
So now that we've got this, let's go ahead and
完成了这一步 现在我们继续
first validate that our and the next we'd go first and create one.
我们先来创建一个验证对象
Here, I'm actually selecting the first 24,000 reviews to train on.
这里 我选择了前 24,000 条评论来进行训练
And I'm just going ahead and say it,
然后
the last we could say these 1,000 reviews can be our test data set.
将最后的 1,000 个评论作为我们的测试集
So I'm going to kind of continue to do that.
我就继续这么用了
You could pick a different training test split,
当然你可以划分不同的训练集和测试集
there's actually another 25,000 in the IMDB data set you could use.
事实上 IMDB 数据集中还能再找到 25,000 条评论供你使用
But, just for the sake of making it easy,
但为了简便起见
I think we're just going to go with this.
我们就用这些数据了
So, we're going to initialize it this way,
首先 我们这样初始化数据
this is actually our default learning rate.
这是我们的默认学习率
&gt;From here, I'm going to put it in so just we can see it.
来自这里 我把它放进来 让大家看得见
The other thing I like to do before we get started is actually test it.
开始之前我还想做的一件事 就是先测试它
So our waits are initialized randomly right now, so
我们的权值是随机初始化的
it shouldn't really predict well at all.
它的预测表现应该并不好
So in this case, testing accuracy is exactly 50% which is,
在这个例子中 测试准确度正好是 50%
if you just guessed, between positive and negative randomly then
如果你在正和负之间随机猜一个值
gear you should get 50% accuracy, and it's actually what we see here.
就会有 50% 的准确率 这也是我们这里所看到的
Which is a good place to start.\ Especially when you have a neural
这是一个不错的起点 特别是当你的神经网络
net with only two predictions,
只有两个预测值时
I really like to see it start off not being biased towards one way.
我很希望看到它在刚开始时不偏向于任何一边
Like if I initialize my weights in such a way where it always predicts one way
如果在初始化权值时 它的预测总是偏向于一边
or always predicts another, or it doesn't get any of them right.
或另一边 或者哪一边都预测不对
Then I kind of scratch my head like, wait a minute,
那我就得停下来了 找找看
something's probably broken here, and so I'll go investigate that first.
是不是哪里出错了 我得先研究一下情况
But, as we can see, it's breaking randomly, and
但是 可以看到 它现在的比例是随机的
it doesn't seem to have any real predictive power at the moment.
目前似乎还没有任何的预测能力
So, now we're going to try to train our network.
那么 我们就要开始训练我们的网络了
Every, something I threw in here a little bit later is that,
我后面加进来的一些代码规定
every 2,500 predictions it will do a new line, wo we can not just see
每预测 2,500 次 另起一新行 所以我们看不到
what the progress is now but, we can kind of see it change over time.
当前的进程 但我们可以看到它如何随时间变化
So now when I'm watching it train there's a few things I'm looking at.
所以 当我观察它训练时 我会注意以下几个方面
First is speed, trying to kind of gauge, how long am I going to be sitting here?
首先是速度 要试着衡量 我要坐在这里等多久
And then I'm also looking at the training accuracy.
然后是训练准确度
So now if you look, so far it's actually not predicting particularly well.
如果你注意观察 会发现它目前预测得并不太好
It's doing just worse than random.
甚至比随机情况下还糟
Which is sort of worse than it was doing before.
比之前的还糟
At this point, when we're 14% of the way through the training data set, and
到这个点 进度已经达到训练数据集的 14% 了
it hasn't even learned anything yet, and it’s like it is doing worst then that.
但它什么都还没学到 看起来比之前还糟
I’m really starting to go okay, something is probably wrong here.
我开始有点怀疑是不是哪里出问题了
They are a few types of neutral nets where at this point it actually
的确有几种神经网络 会在这个点上
does continue print random especially in reinforcement learning,
给出如随机结果般的预测 特别是在强化学习中
however on this dataset we are looking in direct correlation.
但在这个数据集上 我们寻找的是直接相关性
I should be seeing some change right here, so I’m just going to go ahead
现在我应该能看到一些变化才对
a quit this out, we could wait longer, but I just don't think that it's
所以我打算直接退出它 我们可以继续等 但我觉得
going to be a good idea to do that, so we're going to go ahead and hit stop.
这不是一个好主意 所以我选择直接点停止
The natural thing for me to do here is think, okay, so
在这里 我自然会想
the learning rate's too high, right?
会不会是学习率太高了 对吧？
So, when things are doing like this, maybe it's diverging, who knows.
当出现这种情况的时候 可能它未能收敛 谁知道呢
So let's go ahead and adjust this learning rate to b.
那么 让我们将学习率调低一些
Lower and a good way to fill things out is first move by orders in magnitude so
设置新值的一个好办法就是按数量级来调整
I'm going to divide it by ten, reinitialize the network,
我将它除以十 并重新初始化网络
I'm queue slash then compare bounce around a little bit Man,
训练网络然后进行比较 让数据跑一会儿
I'm starting to see kind of the same behavior.
糟糕 好像又和之前的一样
It's not really getting better.
并没有任何改善
Now we'll just train for a second and
现在我们让它训练一会儿
then kind of talk about why was I lowering rate, right?
同时聊聊我为什么要降低学习率
So lowering rate, if you remember from before, is the step side,
如果你还记得 我们之前讲过 学习率也叫步长
it's how big of a jump that it tries to take to reduce the error.
即每次采取多大的一步 去试着减小误差
Probably a standard reason why thins kind of thing happens is that
发生这种情况的一个可能的合理解释就是
it's over shooting, so it's ending up not really any closer
过伸 (overshoot) 因为步长过大
to solving the problem than when it started because it's going to far.
所以它并没有比一开始更接近正确答案
Under shooting means the network trains very very slowly but
另一种：未及 (undershoot) 是指网络训练的速度非常非常慢
it does tend to make progress, this to me could be very very slowly, but
它确实是在一点点改进 但它改得实在太缓慢了
it just doesn't look like it's, training at all.
看起来就像压根没有变化一样
It's just camping out right near 50% and so that's really concerning.
它一直徘徊在 50% 左右 真的让人担忧
And so, we're at our 20% here, I should be seeing something at this point.
我们已经训练了 20% 了 这时应该能看出一些变化了
So we're going to cancel this and we're going to go again.
那么我们取消进程 再来一次
So check this out.
看看这个
Do it one more time.
再重复一遍
Okay, camping out 40%
好的 在 40% 左右徘徊
Create.
很好
Come on, buddy.
加油
It's funny.
有意思
Eventually, these types of metrics become really entertaining to watch.
最终 这些类型的指标看起来非常有娱乐性
And man, I'm actually still kind of surprised, it is not really happening.
我真的有点惊讶 居然一点效果都没有
Here we go, okay, so it's starting to learn a little bit,
哦 哦 开始了 它开始学到一点了
so this is a good sign, right?
这是个好兆头 对吧？
So it's starting to find correlation but it's still going pretty slow, not only,
它开始找到相关性了 但速度仍然很慢 不仅如此
like this is pretty slow as far as your views per second.
每秒处理评论量的速度也很慢
It's only expressing 100 reviews per second but
每秒只能处理 100 个评论
then it's not converting very quickly, right?
并没有快速收敛 对吧？
And I can keep knocking down the learning rate, but
我可以继续调低学习率
the truth is, the more you knock down the learning rate,
事实上 学习率越低
the slower the learning happens, right?
就学得越慢了 对吧？
Whereas before, overshooting, this is still going to continue knocking down.
如果是之前的过伸 我可以继续调低学习率
So one thing that I could do here is continue to tweak the learning rate,
所以 我在这里可以做的一件事是 继续调整学习率
and I could spend all day trying to do that, and
我可以一整天都做这个
I would get incremental Improvements.
获得增量改进
But we're so early on we haven't refined anything, just pose some big
但有点过早了 我们都没做优化
frame questions that we need to really re-evaluate in our neural networks.
只要对我们神经网络的再评估提出一些框架性的问题
Say hey, can we frame this problem so
比如 我们能否重新解构问题
that the correlation is a little more clear, right?
让相关性显示得更清楚明显？
So right now I'm going back, I'm thinking, okay, so, up here.
现在 我返回到上面这里
This is our setup, right, we're counting the words and putting them in here, and
这是我们进行设置的地方 我们对单词计数 将它们放在这里
then it's making a prediction.
然后用它们进行预测
What about this is so difficult for this thing that it's taking this,
是不是它目前的设置对网络来说太难了
so it is converging, but it's just not going very quickly.
它的确在收敛 但速度不是很快
Is there anything that we can do, to make it more obvious for the network for
有没有什么办法 可以让网络更轻易地
it to identify the words that were validated in kind of in our,
识别那些经过验证的单词  在我们的……
well not those lists those were the raw counts.
不是在这些列表中 这些是原始计数
Up here, right so it finds these words more easily, so
在上面这里（pos_neg_ratios） 对 使网络能更容易找到它们
there are two things that I typically do here.
这里 我通常会做两件事
One is I start changing stuff and see if stuff works, and the other one is I dig
第一件是：试着修改一些东西 看看是否有用
deeper in to exactly what's going here, take a look at a few training examples.
另一件是：进一步搞清楚到底发生了什么？ 研究几个训练样例
See that, make sure that the pattern that I think should be in there is
看一看 是否我设想的模式真的在起作用
actually showing up or maybe I have a mistake in my logic.
还是我本身的逻辑就有问题
Nine times out of ten, when something's not training correctly it means
十有八九 当训练不正确的时候 往往意味着
that there's something simple in here that I got backwards,
有一些简单的东西被我弄反了
more than a big complicated change.
而不是什么大的复杂变化
But sometimes it needs to be a big complicated
但有时候 也需要大动干戈
change, it's still training really really quickly.
它仍然在非常快地训练
So I mean if we if we extrapolated this you know things can
如果我们来分析它 有时候它刚开始
train fast in the beginning and then slow down and taper off.
会训练得很快 然后势头减退
So I mean I don't really see this getting much past 61, 62,
我不怎么看到它超过 61% 62%
something in that kind of range, I don't know if they keep training.
大概就在这左右 不知道它是不是还在继续训练
All right.
好的
So now I'm going to ask my question.
那么 现在我来提出我的问题
Okay.
好
How can I make this simpler?
我该如何简化它？
What is the signal in my training data,
哪些是训练数据中的信号？
and what is the noise in my training data?
哪些是训练数据中的噪音？
And that's going to be kind of a topic of the next section, which we're going
这将作为我们下一节的话题
to analyze, and then try to see if we can get this training to happen faster.
我们将分析它 尝试能不能加快训练速度
So feel free to let this kind of train all the way,
你也可以让这个训练继续下去
I don't think it'll get too much past this.
不过我觉得 它正确率不会再提高多少了
And I really feel that we're going to be able to build a better classifier here
我真的认为 我们肯定会构建一个更棒的分类器
in a minute.
马上就好